# NTWARITAGANZWA Denys

Rwandan | Kigali | +250788945193

ntwaridenis@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/ntwaritaganzwa-denys-901194230

### **SUMMARY**

Dedicated climate activist with a mission to promote environmental conservation, sustainable agriculture, and technology innovation in Rwanda. Experienced in community-driven initiatives, actively participating in various activities, including community retreats organised by Wedogreen and the W.C.R.P. Open Science Conference. Currently enrolled in the Spring 2024 Climate Activist Program organised by FXB-USA, enhancing knowledge and skills to contribute effectively to sustainable practices. Committed to bridging the gap between academia and grassroots efforts, focusing on fostering eco-friendly policies and practices for a resilient and sustainable future in Rwanda.

### EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

# E.S Murama – Ruhango District, Rwanda

January 2017 – November 2019

Advanced level certificate,

Relevant coursework: Mathematics, Physics, Geography and Entrepreneurship.

# African Leadership University - Kigali, Rwanda

**April 2021 – May 2024** 

Bachelor of Physics Atmospheric and Climate Science

Relevant coursework: Climate Modeling and Analysis, Environmental Data Analysis, Climate Software Optimization, Programming for Atmospheric Sciences, and Climate Science Consulting.

#### PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

| Climate Advocates | 5 | 01, 2024 - 05, 2024 |
|-------------------|---|---------------------|
|                   |   |                     |

FXB USA – Newyork, USA

• Climate Advocates program.

| Vice President  | 10, 2023 | - Present |
|-----------------|----------|-----------|
| vice r resident | 10, 2023 | – r resen |

## AIESEC - LC Kigali, Rwanda

• Vice President OGx

# Customer Service Representative 04, 2021 – 11, 2022

W.E.C Tech Hub – Kigali, Rwanda

• Customer Service Representative

### Human resource manager 03, 2020 – 03, 2021

Asolat - Kigali, Rwanda

• Human Resource Manager

### **EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

ALU Robotics Club

January 2023 – Present

- Providing technical assistance and guidance to members as they work on their robotics projects.
- Collaborating with the Innovation Officer and other club leaders to develop new initiatives and programs.
- Ensuring that the club's activities align with its mission and values and ensuring all members feel welcome and included.

ALU Wildlife Conservation Club - Volunteer/ Tech Support Edible Insect for Food Sustainability

**April 2023– April 2023** 

## TRAINING AND AWARDS

- Certificate of Global Transformers and Innovators Development Academy for a month.
- Participated in innovative hackathons in cooperation with DELL and Carbon Group Global.
- Training about Wikipedia in Higher Education Initiative at The Moleskine Foundation & Fondazione Aurora
- Networking Certification Short course supported by AFRETEC
- Robotics and Drone Technology Certification Short course supported by AFRETEC
- Big Data Analytics and Visualization Certification Shortcourse supported by AFRETEC
- Embedded Systems and Programming Certification Short course supported by AFRETEC

### **SKILLS**

| <ul> <li>Computer skills</li> <li>Google Apps</li> <li>Communication and<br/>Public Speaking Skills</li> </ul> | <ul><li>Policy Advocacy</li><li>Technology Integration</li><li>Community Engagement</li></ul> | <ul><li> Microsoft Office</li><li> Python</li><li> Networking and Collaboration</li></ul>     |
|--|---|---|
| INTERESTS  |   |   |
| <ul><li>Climate Change Research</li><li>International Climate Activism</li></ul>                               | <ul><li> Green Infrastructure</li><li> Development</li><li> Environmental Justice</li></ul>   | <ul><li>Eco-friendly technology</li><li>Integration</li><li>Climate Policy Advocacy</li></ul> |
| LANGUAGES  • English - Intermediate  | • Kinyarwanda – Native  |   |

### REFERENCES

- Didier NKURIKIYIMFURA, Strategy and Growth Officer at Smart Africa, didier.nkurikiyimfura@gmail.com
- Dr Jean Claude UWAMAHORO, Senior Lecturer at University of Rwanda, <u>uwajclaude@gmail.com</u>
- Dr Joseph NTAHOMPAGAZE, Senior Lecturer at the University of Rwanda, ntahompagazei@gmail.com
- Prof Bonfils SAFARI, Senior Lecturer at the University of Rwanda, bonfilssafari@gmail.com